那是个棘手的问题。
That was a tough problem.
我知道我第一次碰到它很有挑战性
I know when I first ran across it,
that's challenging.
让我们现在就去解决这个问题。
So let's walk through the solution now.
还有这个方案，它会给你一个提示。
And the solution,
it'll give you a hint in the name.
我们会称之为逆向路径，因为这就是我们最终要做的事情。
We'll call it reverse path, because that's
what we're ultimately trying to do.
我们知道我们会得到某种元素我们会得到树的
And we know we're gonna get some sort of
element and we're gonna get the tree.
如果你要通过一个树，它通常以根为代表。
If you're gonna pass someone a tree,
it's generally represented as the root.
一旦您有了根，就可以对整个树进行迭代。
Cuz once you have the root,
you can iterate through the entire tree.
对于许多 JavaScript 开发者来说，很难将其概念化，因为
For many JavaScript developers, it's
difficult to conceptualize this because
你被用来数据结构我把数据结构传给你
you're used to data structures where,
I pass you the data structure,
都是整个数据结构
it's the entire data structure.
类似于数组，对象或集合。
Like an array, or an object, or a set.
而树一般只给你根，
Whereas a tree is generally
only give you the root, and
被称为树的人
that's known as passing you the tree.
所以我们想做的是，知道这个，我们想回到根部。
So what we wanna do is, knowing this,
we wanna walk back up to the root.
顺便说下我们想有办法记录这条路
And along the way,
we wanna have a way of recording the path.
所以当我们跳到这棵树上时，我们就会回到那条完全相同的道路上。
So that when we jump over to this tree,
we walk back down that exact same path.
我想你可以把它想象为倒转字串
I guess you could think of
it like reversing a string.
与我们所做的第一个问题非常相似，实际上，它根本不一样。
Very similar to the first problem we did,
actually, it's not similar at all.
但在概念上，你可以逆向迭代，这就是我们正在做的。
But conceptually, you can iterate over
backwards, and that's what we're doing.
我们正从我们得到的道路上后退
We're iterating backwards
over the path that we get.
那么开始吧，我知道什么 ?
So to start off with, what do I know?
我知道我需要一种方法来存储这条路
I know that I'm gonna need
a way of storing that path.
因为我们知道元素有两部分，他们有父母，
And because we know that elements
have two parts, they have parent,
还有父母会有孩子
and the parent, Is gonna have children.
但这并不真正帮助我们，这些知识。
But that doesn't really help us,
that knowledge.
但我们如何找到指数
But how do we find the index,
还是我们现在的孩子的位置
or the position of the child
that we're currently on?
我想我已经说过了
I think I said it already.
>> indexOf。
&gt;&gt; indexOf.
>> indexOf，是的，如果我们想得到，我们可以说一些元素的 indexOf 。
&gt;&gt; indexOf, yeah, so if we wanted to get,
So we can say indexOf some elements.
这将是路径的一部分。
And this would be one part of the path.
所以如果我们知道孩子的位置就会是 0
So if we know the position of the child,
so it's gonna be 0 or
1 在这种情况下， cuz 很简单，或者 2 或 3 ，它不成熟。
1 in this case, cuz they're pretty simple,
or 2 or 3, it doesn't matte.
可以说 0 ，这也就只有一个了，所以
We can say 0, this will be,
well, there's only one, so
这将为 0，这将为 0。
this will be 0, this will be 0.
这里没有我们在这里的路
And there's no path here
cuz we're at the root.
如果我们重播，我们会说parent.子代，
And if we replay that,
we say parent.children, and
我们把它放了下来，所以我们就把它放了，所以我们说 0， 0， 1。
we replay that path, so
we pop that off, so we say 0, 0, 1.
如果它在树上，它就能得到我们的元素。
And that would get us the element
no matter where it is in the tree.
所以在概念上如果我们理解
So conceptually, if we understand that,
我们可以理解如何创建反向路径。
we can understand how to
create a reverse path.
我想做的第一件事就是我甚至说了我们要想点什么
So the firs thing I wanna do is, I even
said it, since we wanna pop off something,
我要说这条路是个阵列
I'm gonna say the path is an array.
我要把它作为一个数字的数组来存储。
I'm gonna store it as an array of numbers.
我想在我根的时候停下来所以我想说
And I wanna stop when I get to the root,
so I'm gonna say while,
我要说我的父母实际上我要说电流
And I'm gonna say element.parent,
actually, I'm gonna say current.
如果我说指针，我会说指针，在技术上是指针，所以
Should I say pointer, I'll say pointer,
cuz it technically is a pointer, so
那就好
that's good.
我们知道这个循环会一直运作直到我们找到根
We know this while loop will
run until we get to the root,
因为 root 用户将不具有父代。
because the root will not have a parent.
我想做的第一件事就是初始化指针
So the first thing I wanna do is,
I wanna initialize the pointer,
因为我们只是在指着树上的不同节点
because we're just pointing at
different nodes on the tree.
所以我想说，让指针，我们会说它是元素。
So I wanna say, let pointer, and
we'll say it's the elements.
我们要从某个地方开始这是我们的基本案例
We wanna start somewhere,
that's our base case.
那么我们以前做了什么 ?
So what did we do before?
我们想拿到指针的位置
We wanted to get
the position of the pointer.
因此，该位置表示为 0，1或 2，或 3，或 4或 5，
So the position is represented as 0,
1, or 2, or 3, or 4, or 5,
不管它在哪里
wherever it is in that array.
所以我们可以把它打印出来
So we can print that back out.
所以我要说指数是
So I'm gonna say index is,
我们有指针了
we have the pointer.
然后我们去抓父母然后我们去抓孩子们
And we're gonna grab the parent, and
then we're gonna grab the children.
然后我们会说，技术上并不是一个数组。
And then we're gonna say,
it's not technically an array.
它是一个类似阵列的结构，但我不会把它转换成一个阵列。
It's an array-like structure, but
I'm not gonna convert it to an array.
通常情况下，您必须执行类似的操作，然后调用 indexOf。
Normally you'd have to do something
like this, and then you call indexOf.
但我不会为了简单而这么做
But I'm not gonna do that for simplicity.
再一次，一个白板解决方案，我在乎的是你在概念上是有问题的。
Again, a whiteboard solution, I care that
you kind of have it conceptually down.
然后我们会说指针本身的索引
And then we're gonna say
the index of the pointer itself.
这样我们就能在我们需要的阵列中找到位置。
So this will get us the position
in the array that we need.
这会让我们迈出第一步。
So this will get us
the first step in our path.
所以我要说 path.push ，索引本身。
And so I'm gonna say path.push,
the index itself.
然后我就把这个指针移到这个点上。
And then I'm going to move the pointer
up to the parent at this point.
我想知道，父母的孩子在哪里。
Cuz I wanna know where the parent
is in its parent's children array.
所以我要说 pointer = potinter.parent.
So I'm gonna say pointer = pointer.parent.
从概念上来说，这是最困难的部分。
Of the whole thing, I think conceptually
this is the most difficult part.
你要去看看你在哪里是很棘手的
The fact that you have to go up to look
down to see where you are is tricky with
一棵大树它是整个事物的关键
a tree, and
it's kind of the key to this whole thing.
因此，在这个 while 循环中，我们可以每一次推送路径。
So given this while loop,
we can push the path every single time.
所以看这个，这个在位置 0，这个在位置 0，
So looking at this one, this is in
position 0, this is in position 0,
位置 0 ，位置 0，这发生在它们都是 0。
position 0, position 0,
this happens that they're all 0s.
所以在这个 while 循环中，我们将以 1 或 0 的路径结束
So in this while loop, we're gonna
end up with a path that's 1 or 0 or
2 或 3，一些阵列。
2 or 3, some array.
那我们现在怎么办
So what do we do now?
既然我们有反向路径，我们就想把它转至下一棵树。
Since we have the reverse path,
we wanna replay that into the next tree.
所以我要说这个指针现在是根
So I'm gonna say the pointer
is now the root.
所以我现在就切换到这棵树上。
So I've now switched to this tree now.
而我要说的是路径上有任何争论
And I'm gonna say,
while the path has any arguments in it,
我要不停地迭代树
I'm gonna keep iterating down the tree.
哎呀我今天不能拼
Whoops, I cannot spell today.
那我们该怎么下树呢
So how do we move down the tree?
是啊老爸我们要把指针移到下一个孩子
Yeah, pop, we wanna move that
pointer to the next child.
所以我可以说
So I can say pointer is,
我们要去找孩子我们要把他们弄下来
we wanna get to the children cuz
we're maneuvering down the array.
我要说的是帕普波普
And I'm gonna say, path.pop.
这就是一种逆向算法
That's it, that's a reverse algorithm.
当你从概念上思考的时候如果我说
When you think about it conceptually,
if I just said,
给我一个反向路径算法，这不是一个采访者。
give me a reverse path algorithm,
that's not helpful as an interviewer.
但如果我能解释我们想做什么我就能画出来
But if I can explain what we're trying
to do and I draw it out, hopefully,
了解 HTML 和 DOM 结构，您说，有父母和孩子，
understanding HTML and DOM structure, you
say, there's parents and there`s children,
这里有孩子的代表
and here's how children
would be represented.
你可以在概念上处理这个问题。
You can conceptually work this out.
如果你没有得到这个权利，这很有挑战性。
And if you didn't get this right,
it's okay, this is challenging.
但希望它能让你了解树木
But hopefully, it helps grow
your understanding of trees, and
如何向上和向下移动
how to move up and down them.
好吧也许我没警告过你也许我应该警告你
All right, maybe I didn't warn you,
maybe I should have warned you that,
当我们走向终点时，它会变得越来越困难，这就是它的目的。
as we move to the end, it's gonna get more
and more difficult, that's just how it is.
我想给你一个热身的问题，倒串的，就是为了让你去。
I wanna give you a warm up question,
reverse string one, just to get you going.
我本来可以从这个开始的你会觉得这是个愚蠢的课程
I could've started with this, you'd be
like, [LAUGH] this is a stupid course.
我不敢相信我拿了这个课程他在教什么
I can't believe I took this course,
what is he teaching?
但是当我们在这里工作的过程中，希望它在概念上是比较清晰的。
But as we work our way to here, hopefully
it's a little conceptually clearer.